{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is correct for a gated D-type flip-flop?", "opta": "The Q output is either SET or RESET as soon as the D input goes HIGH or LOW.", "optb": "The output complement follows the input when enabled.", "optc": "Only one of the inputs can be HIGH at a time.", "optd": "The output toggles if one of the inputs is held HIGH.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When both inputs of a J-K flip-flop cycle, the output will:", "opta": "be invalid", "optb": "not change", "optc": "change", "optd": "toggle", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Latches constructed with NOR and NAND gates tend to remain in the latched condition due to which configuration feature?", "opta": "asynchronous operation", "optb": "low input voltages", "optc": "gate impedance", "optd": "cross coupling", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 555 timer can be used in which of the following configurations?", "opta": "astable, monostable", "optb": "monostable, bistable", "optc": "astable, toggled", "optd": "bistable, tristable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic S-R flip-flop can be constructed by cross-coupling which basic logic gates?", "opta": "AND or OR gates", "optb": "XOR or XNOR gates", "optc": "NOR or NAND gates", "optd": "AND or NOR gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One example of the use of an S-R flip-flop is as a(n):", "opta": "transition pulse generator", "optb": "astable oscillator", "optc": "racer", "optd": "switch debouncer", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If both inputs of an S-R NAND latch are LOW, what will happen to the output?", "opta": "The output would become unpredictable.", "optb": "The output will toggle.", "optc": "The output will reset.", "optd": "No change will occur in the output.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The equation for the output frequency of a 555 timer operating in the astable mode is: . What value of C1 will be required if R1 = 1 k, R2 = 1 k, and f = 1 kHz?", "opta": "0.33 F", "optb": "0.48 F", "optc": "480 F", "optd": "33 nF", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An astable multivibrator is a circuit that:", "opta": "has two stable states", "optb": "is free-running", "optc": "produces a continuous output signal", "optd": "is free-running and produces a continuous output signal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is another name for a one-shot?", "opta": "monostable", "optb": "bistable", "optc": "astable", "optd": "tristable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The truth table for an S-R flip-flop has how many VALID entries?", "opta": "3", "optb": "1", "optc": "4", "optd": "2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the significance of the J and K terminals on the J-K flip-flop?", "opta": "There is no known significance in their designations.", "optb": "The J represents \"jump,\" which is how the Q output reacts whenever the clock goes HIGH and the J input is also HIGH.", "optc": "The letters represent the initials of Johnson and King, the co-inventors of the J-K flip-flop.", "optd": "All of the other letters of the alphabet are already in use.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the operation of a positive edge-triggered D-type flip-flop?", "opta": "If both inputs are HIGH, the output will toggle.", "optb": "The output will follow the input on the leading edge of the clock.", "optc": "When both inputs are LOW, an invalid state exists.", "optd": "The input is toggled into the flip-flop on the leading edge of the clock and is passed to the output on the trailing edge of the clock.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is one disadvantage of an S-R flip-flop?", "opta": "It has no Enable input.", "optb": "It has a RACE condition.", "optc": "It has no clock input.", "optd": "It has only a single output.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}